<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trillian</title>
    <link>https://trillian.transparency.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Trillian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trillian.transparency.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/discourage-misbehaviour-by-third-parties-in-certificate-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/discourage-misbehaviour-by-third-parties-in-certificate-transparency/</guid>
      <description>--- url: application/discourage-misbehaviour-by-third-parties-in-certificate-transparency layout: glue-page title: Discourage misbehaviour by third parties in Certificate Transparency description: Certificate Transparency Logs use Trillian in verifiable log mode. Certificates are stored as leaves in the Merkle Tree and the browser verifies that certificates are included in the log, and that the log history hasn’t been tampered with. --- Trillan helps you Discourage misbehaviour by third parties in Certificate Transparency    HTTPS security relies on hundreds of Certificate Authorities (CAs) whose job is to issue certificates while checking that the requester is eligible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/discourage-misbehaviour-by-third-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/discourage-misbehaviour-by-third-parties/</guid>
      <description>HTTPS security relies on hundreds of Certificate Authorities (CAs) whose job is to issue certificates while checking that the requester is eligible. For example, they should only issue a certificate for mozilla.org to entities that can prove they control mozilla.org (hopefully only authorized people at Mozilla!).
Unfortunately any CA can issue a certificate for any domain (more or less). So an obscure CA in Russia could issue a legitimate certificate for a UK bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://trillian.transparency.dev/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trillian.transparency.dev/get-started/</guid>
      <description>This is a short video showing how quick download Trillian from github and get it running.
Assumptions:
 You have MySQL installed, listening on the standard MySQL port 3306 (mysql --host=127.0.0.1 --port=3306 connects OK) The root MySQL user does not require a password  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://trillian.transparency.dev/verifiable-data-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trillian.transparency.dev/verifiable-data-structures/</guid>
      <description>--- url: /verifiable-data-structures layout: index title: Verifiable Data Structures description: An overview of Trillian&#39;s verifiable log, verifiable map and log-backed map as well as links to further resources. --- Verifiable data structures    Verifiable log Trillian uses a Merkle tree to implement a verifiable log. Every record inserted into a verifiable log is added as a new leaf in the Merkle tree. In the diagram aboveon the right, the four records are shown along the bottom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add tamper checking to a package manager</title>
      <link>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/add-tamper-checking-to-a-package-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/add-tamper-checking-to-a-package-manager/</guid>
      <description>Advantages  Ensure all users receive exactly the same code for a given package version. Protect you against hacked Github accounts force-pushing malicious code. Minimise the impact of a hacked download server. Protect you from a man-in-the-middle attack serving a tampered package with malicious code. Prevent upstream authors modifying the source code of an existing released version.   How it works Tamper checking means the ability to detect if a package file has been modified since it was first added to the package manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy policy</title>
      <link>https://trillian.transparency.dev/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trillian.transparency.dev/privacy/</guid>
      <description>We use Google Analytics to understand how people arrived on the site and what they did on the site.
This activity is anonymous to us: we cannot identify a user in Google Analytics, and we don’t send identifiable information to them, either.
To disable our use of Google Analytics, enable the Do Not Track setting in your browser. Here are instructions for:
 Chrome Firefox  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliably log all actions performed on your servers</title>
      <link>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/reliably-log-all-actions-performed-on-your-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/reliably-log-all-actions-performed-on-your-servers/</guid>
      <description>Advantages  Guarantee that an audit record is created for all actions performed on your servers. Configure servers to block and report actions that weren&amp;rsquo;t already logged. Any malicious actions are permanently logged, increasing the likelihood of discovery. You can integrate additional code to monitor the log for potentially malicious actions. It simplifies incident response and forensic analysis as you&amp;rsquo;ve got a complete log you can rely on. You can prove to auditors exactly what actions were performed on each server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthen discovery of encryption keys</title>
      <link>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/strengthen-discovery-of-encryption-keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trillian.transparency.dev/application/strengthen-discovery-of-encryption-keys/</guid>
      <description>Key Transparency offers tamper-evident key discovery Key Transparency is a design for a tamper-evident key discovery service that providers of end-to-end encryption services could implement. Key Transparency solves the problem of key discovery using Trillian&amp;rsquo;s Map Mode.
Advantages of Key Transparency  Automate user discovery of end-to-end encryption keys. Provide a shared global view of public keys - everyone should see the same public key for a given username. Increase the difficulty of an attacker performing a man-in-the-middle attack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>