<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transparency.dev Summit on Transparency.dev</title>
    <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transparency.dev Summit on Transparency.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://transparency.dev/summit2025/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A decentralized integrity and transparency model for web applications</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/webcat.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/webcat.html</guid>
      <description>How can we bring transparency and integrity guarantees to a decentralized web, where open-source applications are hosted by many different entities? And how can we clearly communicate these complex trust relationships to end-users? This talk explores the challenges of modeling these dynamics in such ecosystems and presents design ideas from WEBCAT, a fail-closed framework that enables verifiable integrity for web applications.
 Speaker Giulio is a researcher at Freedom of the Press Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day1-afternoon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day1-afternoon.html</guid>
      <description> Break  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day1-morning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day1-morning.html</guid>
      <description> Break  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day2-afternoon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day2-afternoon.html</guid>
      <description> Break  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day2-morning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day2-morning.html</guid>
      <description> Break  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day3-morning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day3-morning.html</guid>
      <description> Break  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast &amp; Hallway Track</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/breakfast-day2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/breakfast-day2.html</guid>
      <description>Join attendees for the hallway track over breakfast before the talks get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast &amp; Hallway Track</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/breakfast-day3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/breakfast-day3.html</guid>
      <description>Join attendees for the hallway track over breakfast before the talks get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate Transparency Breakout Room (Part I)</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/ct-breakout-part1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/ct-breakout-part1.html</guid>
      <description>Certificate Transparency Breakout Room (Part I) The breakout session on Certificate Transparency offers a valuable opportunity for members of the ecosystem to come together to brainstorm ways to make CT more robust and address emerging challenges. Industry practitioners as well as those new to the space are welcome to join.
Preliminary Agenda  TBD   Session Leader: TBD description
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certificate Transparency Breakout Room (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/ct-breakout-part2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/ct-breakout-part2.html</guid>
      <description>Certificate Transparency Breakout Room (Part II) The Certificate Transparency breakout continues after the break.
The breakout session on Certificate Transparency offers a valuable opportunity for members of the ecosystem to come together to brainstorm ways to make CT more robust and address emerging challenges. Industry practitioners as well as those new to the space are welcome to join.
Preliminary Agenda  TBD   Session Leader: TBD description</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing Session</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/closing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/closing.html</guid>
      <description>Closing out the talk portion of the event we will have a fun closing quiz and some awards.
 Talk Recording  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential computing: Trusted computing in the cloud</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/confidential-computing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/confidential-computing.html</guid>
      <description>The witness network safeguards against split-view attacks by transparency logs, but detecting malicious behavior by witnesses is more difficult than with transparency logs. Today&amp;rsquo;s witness network is primarily backed by custom hardware to protect witness private keys, but scaling the network will require an approach that&amp;rsquo;s easier to deploy.
Confidential computing is a hardware backed approach to protecting virtual machines in the cloud, such that neither the cloud providers or operators can tamper with key material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crescendo: Increasing the intensity of binary transparency in the Android ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/crescendo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/crescendo.html</guid>
      <description>In this talk I will be discussing the progress that we made since The Odyssey, Android&amp;rsquo;s First Firmware Binary Transparency [CATS2023]. In particular, I will walk through the process of expanding coverage of the type of binaries that&amp;rsquo;s running on an Android device, and the rationale behind that.
In particular, I will discuss how we expanded coverage from the granularity of an entire firmware as a whole to the APK level, particularly privileged/system APKs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End Transparent Package Registries</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/package-registries.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/package-registries.html</guid>
      <description>Over the last couple of years, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen signed provenance adopted by package registries to provide authenticity and integrity for artifacts, with transparency logs used to record signatures for discoverability of key and identity usage. How can we further leverage transparency to protect all parties involved in the production of software, adding transparency for producers, consumers and distributors?
This talk will delve into software supply chain security for package registries, applying transparency systems to secure publication and distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go module notifications with gopherwatch.org, and more!</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/gopherwatch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/gopherwatch.html</guid>
      <description>Gopherwatch monitors the &amp;ldquo;Go modules&amp;rdquo; transparency log (containing libraries and applications), and sends notifications by email or webhook to users with subscriptions with matching Go module patterns. For example dependencies of your own software, or all software published by your organization, or friends, etc. Gopherwatch.org is a free public service, the code is open source, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to run your own. In this talk, we&amp;rsquo;ll briefly look at Gopherwatch functionality (which, surprisingly, includes a DNS server), look at how Go modules make it into the transparency log, and discuss future work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing transparency in UEFI boot managers</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/uefi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/uefi.html</guid>
      <description>The creation of go-boot, an UEFI boot manager written entirely in bare metal Go, eases use of modern cryptographic frameworks in very early boot stages. We will showcase our integration effort in bringing transparency frameworks to pre-boot environments and their role in defining an API abstraction for bootloader use in Secure Boot and Claimant model enforcement.
 Speakers Andrea Barisani (https://andrea.bio) is an internationally recognized security researcher. Since owning his first Commodore-64 he has never stopped studying new technologies, developing unconventional attack vectors and exploring what makes things tick…and break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Transparency / When Collusion-Based Security Fails</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/kt-brendon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/kt-brendon.html</guid>
      <description>Almost all deployed transparency systems require finding at least one independent and trustworthy third party to help operate the system. Key Transparency systems, however, are deployed by individual organizations to protect their own users. Finding an independent and trustworthy third party in these use-cases is often an overwhelming hurdle to deployment. This talk discusses why, and how the Key Transparency protocol being standardized at IETF solves this problem.
 Speaker Brendan is a freelance cryptography engineer who focuses on developing and deploying standards that make the whole Internet safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/keynote.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/keynote.html</guid>
      <description>The opening keynote kicking off the event will be delivered by TBD
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Make the Internet an App Store (but not in the dystopian way)</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/app-store.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/app-store.html</guid>
      <description>The web browser is the most powerful application platform in existence. As long as you have the right hardware APIs, you can run anything you want in a browser. Well, almost anything. Common wisdom is that end-to-end encrypted applications should not be run in the browser. In fact, Javascript cryptography as a whole is widely Considered Harmful. This is because the server ultimately has control: if the server gives a client malicious Javascript, the client’s end-to-end security guarantees vanish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunch</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day1-lunch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day1-lunch.html</guid>
      <description> Content/abstract here.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunch</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day2-lunch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day2-lunch.html</guid>
      <description>Keynote  Content/abstract here.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merkle Tree Certificates: transparency as the root of trust for the post-quantum age</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/mtcs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/mtcs.html</guid>
      <description>As highlighted in last year&amp;rsquo;s transparency.dev summit, the top quantum-safe signature algorithms require significant increases in key and signature sizes. As a result, a straightforward adaptation of TLS and CT to use these algorithms results in a massive increase in the size of the TLS handshake and the storage and bandwidth requirements for CT logs. Combined with shorter certificate lifetimes, this path would introduce several significant challenges to the CT ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/registration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/registration.html</guid>
      <description>A registration desk will be set up at the reception of TBD. Attendees will pick up their badges there and then be escorted up to the event space. Enjoy some coffee and breakfast and get to know your fellow conference attendees ahead of the talk sessions. Please be aware that attendees will be required to pick up a new badge each day they attend the conference.
Breakfast
 Freshly brewed filter coffee, a selection of Clipper tea infusions Pressed orange juice Selection of pastries and preserves  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible Builds, a very brief summary of the last 12 years and a glimpse into the future</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/reproducible-builds.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/reproducible-builds.html</guid>
      <description>In this lightning talk Holger will briefly present the achievements of the Reproducible Builds project in the last 12 years, covering both upstream developments as well as some distro specific details. The talk will conclude with an outlook into the future and an invitation to collaborate to bring transparency logs into Reproducible Builds projects.
 Speaker Holger Levsen has been a Debian user since almost 30 years and an official Debian member since 2007.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>silentct: A Certificate Transparency monitor that filters out the noise</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/silentct.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/silentct.html</guid>
      <description>Certificate Transparency sets out to make the web&amp;rsquo;s public-key infrastructure auditable. Yet, anyone who&amp;rsquo;s tried to opt in to such auditing quickly notices they get a lot of notifications about legitimately issued certificates. For example, a site that uses Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt regularly gets their certificate renewed once every 60 days. With the upcoming short lived certificates, this could go as low as once every few days. This is a lot of certificate notifications for a single site, not to mention if one is someone managing multiple sites!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split-View protection in centralised transparency logs</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/split-view.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/split-view.html</guid>
      <description>In this talk I will present an approach to achieve split-view protection in centralised transparency log. The technique relies on a few cryptographic building blocks (digital signatures and verifiable random function) and is provably secure against 1/3 corrupted active users, in settings where all communication goes via the transparency log. This is the case of the original design of messaging apps, and may be relevant to other centralised services. For further details, see https://eprint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk 1</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/sigsum.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/sigsum.html</guid>
      <description>Description of Talk 1
 Speaker Description of speaker 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk 2</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/tesseratalk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/tesseratalk.html</guid>
      <description>Description of Talk 2
 Speakers Description of speaker 2
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day3-afternoon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day3-afternoon.html</guid>
      <description> Break  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency.dev Summit 2025 Confirmed Talks</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/</guid>
      <description>Transparency.dev Summit Confirmed Talks   Accepted Talks     Andrea Barisani, Daniele Bianco  Implementing transparency in UEFI boot managers   Giulio Berra  A decentralized integrity and transparency model for web applications   Hayden Blauzvern  End-to-End Transparent Package Registries   Rasmus Dahlberg  silentct: A Certificate Transparency monitor that filters out the noise   Joe DeBlasio  Merkle Tree Certificates: transparency as the root of trust for the post-quantum age   Martin Hutchinson  Verifiable Indexes for a More Usable Transparency Ecosystem   Billy Lau  Crescendo: Increasing the intensity of binary transparency in the Android ecosystem   Holger Levsen  Reproducible Builds, a very brief summary of the last 12 years and a glimpse into the future   Mechiel Lukkien  Go module notifications with gopherwatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency.dev Summit 2025 Schedule</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/organisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/organisation/</guid>
      <description>Transparency.dev Summit 2025 Organisation Organising Committee Anne-Lee Bergman, Amagicom Services AB
Patrick Flynn, Google
Marie Fritzell, Amagicom Services AB
Kat Joyce, Taknira
Fredrik Strömberg, Glasklar Teknik AB
 Program Chairs Rasmus Dahlberg, Glasklar Teknik
Martin Hutchinson, Google  Program Committee Hayden Blauzvern, Google
Philippe Boneff, Google
Al Cutter, Google
Joe DeBlasio, Google
Grégoire Détrez, Mullvad VPN
Edona Fasllija, ASIT, TUGraz
Alexis Hancock, EFF
Ryan Hurst, Peculiar Ventures
Dennis Jackson, Mozilla</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency.dev Summit 2025 Schedule</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/schedule/</guid>
      <description>Transparency.dev Summit 2025 Schedule The schedule for the 2025 summit is currently a work in progress and may change.
Talks that have been accepted so far can be seen here.  Full Schedule     Monday, 20th October  9:00am  Registration    10:00am  Welcome    10:15am  Keynote    10:45am  Break    11:00am  Certificate Transparency talks (x3)    12:30pm  Lunch    2:00pm  Certificate Transparency talks (x3 with break)    3:45pm  Breakout sessions    5:00pm  Lightning talks    5:30pm  Closing remarks    Evening  Activities (TBD)   Tuesday, 21st October  9:00am  Welcome    9:15am  Talks (x5 with break)    12:30pm  Lunch    2:00pm  Talks (x3 with break)    3:45pm  Breakout sessions    5:00pm  Lightning talks    5:30pm  Closing remarks    Evening  Social dinner at Restaurant Tegel (within walking distance of venue)   Wednesday, 22nd October  9:00am  Welcome    9:15am  Quiz    10:00am  Lightning talks (unscheduled)    10:45am  Breakout sessions    12:00pm  Close        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparent transparency hardware</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/hardware.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/hardware.html</guid>
      <description>Hardware security modules (HSMs) and transparency technology complement each other. For example, a transparency capable HSM can help adding transparency to legacy systems, such as UEFI Secure Boot, which uses RSA signatures and is unlikely to support spicy signatures anytime soon. To do that, we need an HSM that is sufficiently open and flexible.
This talk will explain how the radically open-source Tillitis TKey and Tillitis HSM work, and report the current state of development of our transparency apps for these devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verifiable Indexes for a More Usable Transparency Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/verifiable-indexes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/talks/verifiable-indexes.html</guid>
      <description>Transparency logs, the bedrock of systems like Certificate Transparency and the Go SumDB, promise unparalleled verifiability. But this promise comes with a hidden cost. How can a user find their specific entries (their domain&amp;rsquo;s certificates, or their software&amp;rsquo;s releases) within a log containing billions of entries, without downloading terabytes of data or blindly trusting a centralized indexer? This trade-off between efficiency and verifiability has held back the full potential of transparency adoption and verification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome and Introduction</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/intro.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/intro.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome and introductory session to kick off Transparency.dev Summit</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>⚡ Lightning Talk: Lightning talk title</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/digitalid.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/digitalid.html</guid>
      <description>Lightning talk description
 Speaker Lightning talk speaker description</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🌟 Reception 🌟</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/reception.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/reception.html</guid>
      <description>Details to come</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎯 Evening Reception</title>
      <link>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day1-afternoon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transparency.dev/summit2025/break-day1-afternoon.html</guid>
      <description>All event attendees are invited to join us for an evening reception with food, drinks and some fun 🎯! More details to be shared.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
